[Music]
[Applause]
me
[Music]
is this the last house to close up today
afraid not
still got the lennox place i wonder why
captain linux didn't clear out his
family when the cholera took hold but i
thought he didn't know better yeah his
wife refused to leave
pretty thing but stubborn
pray she'd miss a dinner party can you
imagine we call over about nobody's left
then don't think so
just have to close up the place now
somebody come here at once
i command someone to help me or i'll
scream
where is everybody
stale
lazy servants
mother
father
why do they always leave me alone
what are you doing in my house
your house yes i am mary lennox captain
lennox's daughter i can't believe it
she's actually been forgotten i have not
been forgotten
find my servants find my parents poor
kid there's nobody left to find love the
servants have all fled listen missy your
parents died from the cholera
and carried away in the night they can't
be dead
who will take care of me don't you worry
love
we'll find your home
home
now i can hardly hear the word and to
think of all the times i've heard
[Music]
his head
i don't want to hear it
please don't get my hopes up
[Music]
[Applause]
other people say
as long as i'm alone
[Music]
well mary i suppose i should tell you
something about your uncle's house
misselthwaite manor is a queer place
very gloomy
it's 600 years old on the edge of a moor
there are over a hundred rooms though
most of them are shut up and locked
mrs medlock if i want to know anything
i'll ask my aunt your aunt has been dead
for 10 years
10 years and your uncle's not fond of
children
[Music]
home home is a memory of a bed
where i woke and found the final
[Music]
please page get my hopes up
hurry up look sharp though we haven't
got all day
[Music]
my
missile plate
impressive don't you think
[Music]
well
here we are
follow me
i'll show you to your room
[Music]
come on
this is good
talk good evening
is everything going well
as well as we could hope
thank you very much mr medlock
good night
[Music]
why didn't my uncle say hello that
wasn't your uncle archibald that was dr
craven his brother when shall i meet my
uncle then your uncle does not wish to
see you
and my job is to make sure he's not
disturbed and that he doesn't see what
he doesn't want to see
[Music]
well here you are this room is where
you'll live and you must keep to it
i will do as i like
you will do as the master wishes
i'll have your supper sent up to you
don't bother i'm not hungry
a horrible place this is
[Music]
[Applause]
i wish i were back in india i wish i
were anywhere but here
good morning miss mary
time to rise and shine poor dear you
must have been tired falling asleep in
your traveling clothes
who are you hi martha
did you sleep well dear of course not
this is the noisiest house i've ever
been in
i
the winds make a terrible uproar at
night
watering round the house and squalling
in all the nooks and crannies
it's a wonder anyone gets any sleep at
all are you going to be my servant oh i
do bits and bobs of housework and i'm to
keep an eye on you but you shouldn't
need much waiting on then who's going to
dress me can't you dress yourself it's
not a question of it's a question
of won't
it's just not the custom in india
strange customs in india
things are much stranger here well here
in yorkshire is the custom for children
to put on their own clothes i
you'll have the knack of it in no time
[Music]
most pathetic excuse for a garden i've
ever seen
hey why'd you do that
don't you dare let that happen again
stop tormenting poor creatures that
never caused you any harm who are you to
tell me what to do um ben weather stuff
i see to the gardens
then why are all the gardens dead
you would have been fired in india if
the gardens look like this
gardens aren't dead lasts it's just
winter soon it'll be spring you'll see
green crocuses and daffodils will push
up through this very soil
where will i find them maybe if you
didn't throw sticks at robin he'd be
your friend and sure
i don't need any help and i don't need
any friends suit yourself
we're a good bit alike we too we're both
sour as we look and got the same nasty
tempers fancy such insolence from a
garner
um
that's very rude cat you mustn't do that
i see you've met darjeeling
whose cat is this she used to be your
aunt lillian's cat but for years she's
belonged to no one
belong to no one
then she shall belong to
me what is that noise
it's only the uh
wind dear
drink your teeth
i'm finished with my tea
it's not only the wind
[Music]
uh
i'm your cypress or eyes
i'm going back to my room
oh then dear you needn't do that
and if here i took there and you'll be
as right as rain
i've brought something for you what is
that for
for
not got skipping ropes in india
[Music]
just watch me i'll show you how it's
done
you're talking your dress and your goals
[Music]
when i was 12 i could skip to a hundred
of course i was in practice then and not
so fat
i'm going to skip to a hundred perhaps
on the more you'll meet my brother
dicken
he talks to the animals and they talk to
him
some say he's an animal charmer there
are no animal charmers except in india
of course
come along darjeeling
come along then darjeeling darjeeling
won't go out
she's strictly a house cat a house cat
you're just a scaredy cat
one
two
three
four
oh
[Music]
no flowers yet mary
hello robin
[Music]
where are you going
i can't climb that wall
[Music]
there has to be a door around here
somewhere
there's no way in
[Music]
[Applause]
93 94 95 96 97 98 99
[Music]
it's here
spring is here
i must tell ben
[Music]
need any help
no i don't need any help
[Music]
you must be taken and you must be
mistress murray
pleased to meet you
did you really throw a stick at robin
how'd you know about that
you are an animal charmer anybody can
understand the animals if they really
want to
he likes you
do you know what's behind the walls
nobody knows what's behind the walls no
one's been allowed inside being locked
up for ten whole years i wonder why
let's come back tomorrow and find a way
in i must get in there we aren't
supposed to
but all right i better get back it's
getting late nice to meet you
tomorrow then
[Music]
dickens wonderful i thought you two
would hit it off robin talks to me you
know ticking you all about the stick i
threw
[Music]
mary you must go to your room and clean
yourself up the master wants to see you
[Music]
come on i'll help you get ready
don't be afraid
i'm your uncle archibald
i'm not frightened
are you well
yes
i'm sorry for your loss child
i know how you must feel
it doesn't matter
you know
i almost forgot you were here
i
intended to send you a
governess or a nurse but uh i forgot i
don't need anyone to take care of me
please don't make me have a governess
i'm
i'm just getting used to it here you're
trembling
oh don't be so frightened
you may do what you like
really of course
a child like you couldn't do any harm
is there
anything you want i mean toys books
dolls
might i have a bit of earth to grow
things in
someone i cherished very much loved the
earth
and things that grow
was that my aunt lillian
yes
yes it was
well
mary i'm traveling to scotland tonight
on business i'll be gone a considerable
time
while i'm gone mrs medlock will be in
charge
yes sir
[Music]
goodbye
goodbye mary
[Music]
i wonder what that noise is
it certainly doesn't sound like any wind
i ever heard before i'm going to find
out what that is once and for all
[Music]
you deserve to be in charge here at
misselthwaite
your brother doesn't appreciate it for
heaven's sake he's hardly ever here yes
well
that is true
don't forget this
i've put in a few extra pounds from the
household account
i know what a time you've had of it
good night mrs medlock
good night dr craven
mary legends
what are you doing out of your room
[Music]
oh
stop it let go of me look
[Music]
you were told to keep to your room
you have defied my orders and that is
something i will not allow
[Music]
i'm supposed to meet dicken today
what am i going to do
[Music]
don't go please
do you want me to follow you
[Music]
wait
don't go so fast
[Music]
thank you aren't you coming
dicken
i'm too late
if only you could talk to me like you
talked to dicken
maybe then you could tell me where the
key is
i don't understand
[Music]
[Laughter]
all the mysteries of nature are clear
if you listen
to the meaning
not the word
every nay every winnie every howl every
bleat a
[Music]
not
can you help me do you know where the
key is
in the hollow
between the branches of the tree
here it is
i found it
yes you found it
[Music]
[Applause]
a guard
a secret garden
still it is
i must be the first person who's been in
here for years
this used to be the loveliest spot in
all of england
is that why you wanted to show it to me
oh yes
you see i remember it the way it was
it must have been beautiful once
what are you two up to
[Music]
you do remind me of your aunt lillian
what was she like
the prettiest
kindest lass ever to grace the manner
[Music]
oh robin look at these little things
it's like magic
i must tell dickens
a garden of my very own
[Music]
dicken dicken i have a wonderful
surprise
whoa bath follow me
it's just mistress murray i found the
way into the garden come on i'll show
you let's go
i've climbed that tree for years
it's a wonder i've never found it before
well i was waiting to tell the right
person
yes he was waiting for me it was magic
that told him it was me well blow me
down you've learned robin yes i have
she wants to see the garden do you think
we should go in there
after all
it is locked
uncle archboard said i could have any
piece of earth i like and i like this
one
after all nobody's using it
it's a queer pretty place
almost like a dream
[Music]
a body might think this was dead but i
don't believe it is not down to the
roots
how do you know
see that it's wick as uri
i'm glad it's wick
what's wick
wick that's yorkshire it means it's got
life in it well then i want them all to
be wick
with a little tending by summer they'll
be fountains of roses
why who did this
i did
they were so little and they looked as
if they couldn't breathe
a gardener come to done better
he there will be a sight
there's a lot of work to do here
i can dig and pull up weeds whatever
needs to be done hey i wouldn't want to
make it all clipped and and span
it's nice like this
with things running wild swinging and
catching all of each other
yes
it will be a magical garden
oh i wish you'd been there
it once was a beautiful garden you've
been in the garden
mary you can understand me yeah the
garden's mouth is so full of fabulous
smells
but it's so dangerous out there
[Music]
that's not just the wind wuthering it's
different
it sounds like someone's crying
you know every inch of mistlethwaite can
you help me find out what's making that
noise you don't want to find that noise
you do know something show me
if i must
[Music]
i need a candle i don't
follow me
[Music]
oh
wow
[Music]
darjeeling oh sorry
those rats were as big as poodles what a
scaredy cat
you can't leave me alone i don't know
how to get back
don't worry we're almost there
[Music]
we're here
the coast is clear
let's go
[Music]
[Applause]
here we go i'm right behind you
[Music]
who are you
are you a ghost
no
are you
i am colin craven
who are you
i'm mary lennox from india mr craven is
my uncle he's my father your father
nobody told me uncle archbald had a son
that's because i won't let them
everyone in misselthwaite must do as i
say
because i'm ill
if i grow up
i'll probably be a hunchback like my
father
but no one believes i shall live to grow
up
what a strange house this is
everything is locked up and kept secret
no wonder you cry i do not you do too
i know because you keep me up
i really wish you wouldn't make such a
fuss
what's this
nothing leave it alone
i said leave it alone
i don't want to see it
if you tell me why you keep it covered
i'll tell you a secret
i've never had a secret
it's a picture of my mother
my father hates me because she died when
i was born
my parents died
in an epidemic in india oh you're all
alone
as well
i have a garden a secret garden
it's a wondrous place
tell me all about it
robin lives there and the crocuses are
coming up and by summer they're going to
be lots and lots of roses it will be as
beautiful as the gardens in india india
my father brought me something from
india once
it's very handsome
oh mary
i want to see the garden ever so badly
why don't you come with me
i can't
i can't walk
dicken could push a wheelchair dicken
martha's brother he's the only other
person who knows about the garden good
and he shall push my wheelchair and we
can go to the garden just the three of
us uh oh i better get back to my room
before mrs medlock catches me
i'll come back tomorrow i promise
[Music]
just dream about the garden
i want to go outside now
no
not now my boy
i don't think that's the best thing for
you right now i am not your boy and they
don't care what you think i if you go
outside you'll catch your death if i'm
not going to live anyway what difference
does it make i i
i tell you what my lad
a journey outside is out of the question
today but i leave a prescription for you
with mrs medlock
and we'll see how you are in a week hmm
what could possibly have got into that
boy
i can't imagine his going out would hurt
anything
in fact
there's always the chance he could make
him feel better precisely the problem
better double the prescription doctor
do you think that's why is
look what a tantrum he just threw the
child is out of control
right you are
be careful with this
it's strong than he's used to
please let it still be there please
[Music]
it's even prettier than before
yeah i've brought these tools let me
show you how to use them
[Music]
right
that's right murray the earth has got to
breathe
digging do you know about colin what
does that know about him
well i've met him
he can't walk
he's afraid he might be a hunchback if
he grows up
and he thinks his father hates him do
you think his father hates him no and he
ought to think like that
no lad could get well with thoughts like
those if he were out here with us
he'd be watching for butts to break on
the rose bushes not thinking dreary
thoughts i believe you're right
[Music]
i don't know about that
there's something you ought to know
ten years ago mr craven was happier than
he'd ever been in his life
they had spent a hundred other days just
like this one
[Music]
he asked miss craven to go inside but
she loved that garden so
then
something terrible happened
colin was born later that day
lillian was determined to see that child
into the world
but
she died soon afterward poor wretched mr
craven only came to the garden once
after that to lock it up
forever
[Music]
robin don't you see
colin must come here
the fall killed his mother and he thinks
his birth did
i'm sure learning the truth would heal
him most of all i think you're right
murray
besides i think miss lillian would have
liked for him to know this garden
[Music]
get away from me
and you'll feel better no i won't
what do you think you're doing
not talking to you
what are you doing here you have
disobeyed me again
go to your room
we must leave master colin to rest i
want mary to stay i want you to go
medlock everyone must do as i say
very well master colin
you tell me what you're screaming about
this instant
stop you stop stop i can scream louder
and longer than you
you
you didn't come to see me today that's
right i was outside with dicken you
promised to come see me you promised i
didn't see what time
you might not see dicken anymore you
will only see me i'll see dick and all i
want he's the finest boy i've ever met
if i stop seeing anyone it will be you
oh
go ahead scream till you're blue
there's nothing wrong with you it's just
hysterics and temper just hysterics
hysterics hysterics felt a lump on my
back it started
i'm going to end up just like my father
i'll wager there's nothing the matter
with your back here let me have a look
there's not a single lump here but i
felt it all you feels backbone lumps and
you can only feel them because you're so
thin i've got backbone lumps and they
used to stick out too until i got fatter
do you think
i could
live to grow up if you stop by you're
screaming and get some fresh air i don't
see why you shouldn't live to be a
hundred do you think so would you tell
me about your day please
how was the garden
oh colin you wouldn't believe how fast
it's growing did you tell dick and about
me yes
he said he'd be happy to push your
wheelchair to the garden can't go to the
garden why not
dr craven and mrs medlock won't let me
go out
i thought everybody has to do as you say
we're going out and we want to be left
alone medlock master colin you mustn't
forget that you're a very sick boy
that is precisely what i must forget
come on mary come on dicken we're off
that girl is trouble
she's a bad influence on colin
can't you see she's undermining our
positions
[Music]
you take the chair mary well i get on
with things here
it's wonderful
to think i never knew it was here and
it's only spring
just imagine what it will look like in
full bloom
i can imagine a garden full of sunlight
streaming down
nourishing even the tiniest buds as they
spring up from the ground
they'll be higher synthetic
we'll watch it
as it
grows
spring will have brought us a rain cloud
nature's great big watering can
can you imagine us pruning the leaves
till my face is roasted
flowers come alive flourish and survive
out from under the heaviest
[Music]
color will be seen red and blue and
green we'll be turning up every last
storm
[Music]
growing growing
what are you scallywags doing in garden
who are you
get out
this is mrs craven's garden nobody's
allowed to go inside nobody
you're master colin of course i'm master
colin who else would i be i knew your
mother what's that been doing with the
self hiding out and letting people think
you're a half witch and a i'm
not a half wit and i can walk
if i want to
[Music]
i knew he shouldn't be in here colin are
you all right
just shaking
he'll be right as rain in a minute or
two don't worry mary
i'll be all right
i'm so glad
right then clear out the lot of you
now see here
oh ben we love the garden so
see how we're tending it
aunt lillian would have liked the garden
to be brought back to life i just know
it
i
that she would have i want to help in
the garden
i'll work on it every day
oh she'll get stronger and stronger
look ben he can do it he can do what he
can
i shall make my father proud of me i
will learn to walk
it will be a surprise
and no one must say anything about it
ah
you'll make a man yet
god bless thee
did you see how flushed master colin was
when he came home yesterday i certainly
did
he seems to be getting more and more
difficult
and louder too
before that wretched mary came to
mistlethwaite everything was fine just
fine she's upsetting colin and ruining
my plans i had everything under control
till now
but what can we do
here you must write to your brother we
will simply have to have the girl sent
away is that necessary
she's just a young girl after all if we
are to keep control of missile freight
we can't tolerate any change in the
order of things
you wouldn't want those shortages in the
house accounts to be discovered would
you
certainly not
certainly not there's no question about
it dr craven we have to do this well
if you think so
dear archibald
i'm writing to you all on a matter of
great urgency
how does that sound keep writing
miss mary has discovered master colin
her bad influence is putting him in
great danger i got it she has enticed
him on outings that are pushing his
frail little body beyond its limits
who knows what danger might beset him
what dire consequences might befall him
to what depths his illness might
progress
really medlock
don't you think that's laying it on a
bit thick
therefore
in the best interests of the boy i
recommend that miss mary be sent away
upon your reply we will find an
appropriate boarding school
oh don't be so glam colin we may not be
able to go out today but i've got a
surprise for you a surprise
what sort of surprise did you know
mistlethwade has a hundred rooms
mary
no
[Music]
this is what i wanted you to see
it's your father's study
[Music]
look marry elephants
just like the one father gave me that's
where my elephant belongs
[Music]
never seen her smile before
mary
now it almost seems that she's smiling
at me
do you think she could be i'm so glad i
found you what's the matter mrs
medlock's trying to get your uncle to
send you away
[Music]
i overheard that old witch and dr craven
writing a letter to master archibald
they wrote that you're a bad influence
on colin they said you're making him
sicker i that's nonsense i
don't think so
and i don't think mr craven will either
calling adores miss mary the children
get on so well together if there's one
thing i dislike more than difficult
little girls it's meddling housemate but
mrs med i think eve's dropping an
insubordination of sufficient grounds
for dismissal
pack your things
you can't sack martha i shall tell my
uncle about your lies and wickedness
i've had enough of you merry lennox
let go let's go
mary
[Music]
perhaps now you'll think twice before
causing more trouble
[Music]
help
let me out
[Music]
now what shall i do
why do you look so glum
another cat got your cream mrs medlock
is sending me away i'd scratch her eyes
out but she's too scary
if there were only some way for me to
contact uncle archibald i know he
wouldn't send me away
think
what we could really use is a carrier
pigeon
a delicious pigeon
that's it
what you're brilliant robin can take a
message to uncle archibald
[Music]
oh
it's no use i've gotten too big
oh well
that's that
maybe not
you must do me a favor
anything
just ask go to the garden and get robin
you're the only one who can save us
outside
not this old cat
it's out of the question
not possible i i don't go outside
it's dangerous out there storms and
lightning
there's no lightning now come on
darjeeling we're all afraid of things
muster your courage
what courage think of poor colin you
must be brave
i'll do my best
[Music]
thank you darjeeling thank you
go to robin and tell him to come here
and hurry
when this is over i better get a coat
full of cream
[Music]
robin
wake up
[Music]
robin please it's darjeeling
you haven't been out of the house for
for years
no i haven't have i
well we all get over things
you haven't seen any lightning have you
why are you here
mary needs you she's in trouble go
quickly
[Music]
oh thank goodness you're here
what's the matter ass you once told me
you know where my uncle stays in
scotland
you must take a message to him here i've
written a letter
[Music]
scotland
wait a second
wait just a second
[Music]
colin needs you
come at once
flies you've never flown before robin
it's ever so urgent
yes
if you please mom i'm here for murray
and colin the children are staying in
today master colin's not feeling well
but yesterday today the children are not
going out
[Music]
what could the matter be
yesterday colin seemed weak as you are i
where's mary i want to see mary not
today master colin
you're far too agitated
[Music]
if you calm down i know you will feel
better here drink this
no i won't
i don't want your powders and potions i
want to see mary
and if you don't let me i'll have you
sacked
we'll see about that
[Music]
listen to the child
his face is red his body's hot he won't
stop screaming
if he doesn't explode i will
sounds like you need the rest more than
young colin
don't you understand anything
you fool
that child is getting better and better
every day
a bit of good luck
oh
good doctoring
if colin becomes healthy then you will
never be master of mistletoe we must
control that boy
yes
i suppose you're right
perhaps just a little elixir to
suit his nerves
i'll dip into the household funds and
see if i can thank you in an appropriate
way
thank you mrs medlock
that will be most appreciated
so
[Music]
let me out
you'll pay for this
someone help
[Music]
look mother
i can almost walk
i can keep watch from here
[Music]
who is it
who's there
[Music]
have you
noticed how quiet it is
why
it's so quiet you could hear a mouse
drop
don't like it
not a bit
i have to get out of here somehow
something terrible may have happened to
colin i know where she keeps her keys
please try and get them
hurry
how do i always get myself into these
things
because
i am the bravest one of all
oh
dicken what are you doing here i got
worried where have you been
i've been left here alone and i haven't
seen mary for two days i have to get you
out of here
be careful mrs medlock
this is potent stuff
too much could prove fatal
this is the maximum dosage
i'll go up and take a look at him before
i leave
ah
seems that i've left my stethoscope in
the
carriage plummet you in colleen's room
man
certainly dr craven if you like
one two three as i count to ten
my final patience is wearing thin
i'm sick and tired of this
[Music]
till now i think i've been too polite to
claim what's new me is my
right and fine night
[Music]
and when the deed is over and done
i will have fought this battle and one
and i'll be right where i have deserved
to
be for so long
when this man and his wretched boy
are thrown aside like a broken toy
i will enjoy that the manna
will be mine
the manner will be mine
[Music]
hurry it's worse than you thought
medlock's trying to poison colin
oh no
oh
quick hide
[Music]
mary
we've gotta hurry
let's go
what's going on i don't have time to
explain we've gotta hurry
[Music]
[Applause]
i know who's behind this
we've got to find him
[Music]
dicken you go and fetch help
colin and i will wait in the garden
we'll be safe there
[Music]
where could they have gone
could they be down there
they wouldn't be down there
their garden's dead locked up forever
now we've got them
it's magnificent
more beautiful than we ever dreamed
you thought you could hide in mrs
craven's garden did you
for a long time now you have defied me
mary lennox
no more
you leave her alone medvek my father
your father what your father cares
nothing for you he wouldn't care if you
lived or died that's why he's never here
that's not true there you go defying me
again
i am in charge of mistletoe
and soon i will be in charge of
mistletoe manor forever more
is that so mrs medlock
father uncle archibald
robin found you
archibald
we have a serious problem this willful
child is ruining everything
she's put poor call in a terrible risk
and and and yes yes we have a very
serious problem that's not true
don't believe them father it was mary
who helped me get well mary in the
garden
[Music]
there's magic in this garden i can see
that colin
i can see that perfectly well
i trusted and listened to you both but
mr craven
you exploited my grief and came between
me and my child now archibald surely you
can't think i had anything to do with
this
you should have known better
no
i should have known better
get out of my sight the both of you
leave it once
but i'm sure the constable will want to
have a word with you
[Music]
so
this was the piece of earth you wanted
so badly
it looks so sad and lonely
it will never be sad again
you've worked wonders in here
are we going to stay together now father
you me and mary
yes
call him
you
me
and mary
home now i can finally say the word
and to think of all the times it made me
cry
home home is a very special bird
who
[Music]
i have seen my wishes coming true
loving you has shown
my future's right here with you
cookie jar
[Music]